John Carter

johnacarter@gmail.com (770) 598-7096

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT HTML, CSS, Javascript

COMPRESSION Mpeg, MP4, GIF

EXPERIENCE

Hachette Book Group

Principal Systems Administrator Jan 2014 - Present

Provided end-user support for a Java-based chat application

- Developed detailed documentation both for customer consumption and internal
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Hachette Book Group

Senior Systems Administrator Nov 2010 - Jan 2014

Provided end-user support for a Java-based chat application

- Developed detailed documentation both for customer consumption and internal
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Digi-Net Technologies, Inc.

Director of Technology Dec 2005 - Nov 2010

Provided end-user support for a Java-based chat application

- Developed detailed documentation both for customer consumption and internal
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Digi-Net Technologies, Inc.

Senior Systems Administrator Mar 2002 - Dec 2005

Provided end-user support for a Java-based chat application

- Developed detailed documentation both for customer consumption and internal
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Digi-Net Technologies, Inc.

Product Support Manager Aug 2000 - Mar 2002

Provided end-user support for a Java-based chat application

- Developed detailed documentation both for customer consumption and internal
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Digi-Net Technologies, Inc.

Product Support Engineer Apr 2000 - Aug 2000

Provided end-user support for a Java-based chat application

- Developed detailed documentation both for customer consumption and internal
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

EDUCATION

University of Oklahoma

May 2011 - Dec 2013

Bachelor - Information Technology GPA: 4.0

INTERESTS

Wildlife

- Ferrets
- Unicorns